# **SEAN RYAN**

I am a web developer with extensive professional experience in digital marketing and communications. Strong JavaScript fundamentals form the backbone of my full-stack development toolkit. My goal is to be a standout member of a development team by combining my talent for writing clean and intuitive code with stellar written and verbal communication skills.

## **PROJECTS**

# Think Tank Source Code | App Hosted on Netlify

A real-time chat application build with React and Firebase

- Implemented a Firebase Realtime Database to store and relate user, room, and message data objects
- Connected the Firebase backend to a single-page application built with React
- Implemented one-click user authentication via Google, Facebook, Github and email using FirebaseUI
- Wrote component methods to perform create, read and delete operations on database objects via the Firebase API
- Deployed with Netlify

## **Command Line Contacts Source Code**

A command line application for storing and retrieving contacts

- Built a Node.js app that collects user input from the command line with Inquirer
- Installed Sequelize to store and retrieve input in a Postgres database
- Used Jasmine to yrdy each feature of the app

#### RGB Color Picker Source Code | App Hosted on GitHub Pages

A game in which the user must select the color that matches an RBG value

- Built a system to generate random RGB colors using built-in vanilla JavaScript methods
- Wrote reusable functions the game's "easy" and "hard" modes

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

**Association for Computing Machinery**, Digital Communications Coordinator Sept. 2015 - Present

- Tripled average quarterly member acquisitions via Google AdWords
- Doubled average monthly follower growth on ACM's official Facebook and Twitter accounts
- Manage all search, display and social media advertising for a global scientific society serving computing professionals
- Write social media, web, and email marketing content targeted to software engineers and computing researchers
- Analyze social-driven web traffic using Google Analytics to continuously improve member acquisition and retention

# SIS International Research, Project Manager

Feb. 2012 - Sept. 2015

- Oversaw multi-city qualitative and quantitative research projects through initial planning to client delivery
- Moderated focus groups and in-depth interviews for research projects in cities across the US
- Wrote final reports presenting research findings and recommendations to clients

Cell: (203) 731-4234

Email: seanpryan89@gmail.com

GitHub: sean-p-ryan

Portfolio: <a href="www.seanpryan.dev">www.seanpryan.dev</a>
Ll: <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/seanryan11">www.linkedin.com/in/seanryan11</a>
Dev: <a href="https://dev.to/seanpryan">https://dev.to/seanpryan</a>

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**JavaScript** 

CSS

HTML

**Bootstrap** 

SASS

Git

**GitHub** 

React

NPM

SQL

**Postgres** 

Node.js

TDD

**BDD** 

**Jasmine** 

### **EDUCATION**

#### bloc.io

Nov. 2018 - July 2019
Full-Stack Web Development
(React, Node.js, JavaScript and CS fundamentals) in a project-based online course

# NYU Continuing Education (Front-end Foundations)

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018 Front-end end web development with an emphasis on mobile first layout techniques

## **Hamilton College**

Aug. 2007 - May 2011

Degree: B.A. in History, English

Literature